<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" 
xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  
  <channel>
    
    <title>Potential: A Physics Careers Podcast</title>
    <link>http://dev.wripa.ac.uk/potential</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&#169; WRIPA</copyright>
    <itunes:author>WRIPA</itunes:author>
    <description>
Potential is a careers podcast with a difference. In each episode, physics graduates share their stories about the good times, the hard times, the ups and the downs of starting a career. It’s a podcast about falling over, and then picking yourself back up again. It’s about finding your path, and then changing direction completely. If you're in the middle of your physics degree and wondering, "What do I do next?" ... we're here to help. Hosted and produced by Chris Stewart, and brought to you by WRIPA, the White Rose Industrial Physics Academy.
    </description>
    <itunes:type>serial</itunes:type>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>WRIPA</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>info@wripa.ac.uk</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:image
      href="https://dev.wripa.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/potential-logo-2.png"
    />
    <itunes:category text="Science">
      <itunes:category text="Physics"/>
    </itunes:category>
    <itunes:category text="Education">
    </itunes:category>
    <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    
    <item>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:episode>5</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
      <title>The Benefit Of Hindsight</title>
      <description>
In this final episode of this season of Potential we ask our physics graduates, if they could sit down with their younger selves back in first or second year of university, what advice would they give? What have they learned since they graduated that might help? We collected all that advice into five buckets of wisdom — and who knows, maybe some of it will resonate with you too.
Hosted and produced by Chris Stewart. Featuring all our graduates: from Leeds, Nicola Brown, Jonathan Foster and Lottie Tant; and from york, Sam Bourne, Xanthe Edge, Natalie Greenwood, Calum Lennox and Harry Phillips
      </description>
      <link>href="http://dev.wripa.ac.uk/potential"</link>
      <enclosure 
        length="24459417" 
        type="audio/mp3" 
        url="https://dev.wripa.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Potential_Advice_s1e5.mp3"
      />
      <guid>potpods1e5</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:24:56</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:episode>4</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
      <title>You're An Imposter</title>
      <description>
Life doesn’t always go to plan. Big challenges can hit you out of nowhere and make you trip, sending you crashing to the ground. And then you have to find a way to pick yourself up, dust yourself off, and move forward again. In this episode we hear from three of our physics graduates who went through some seriously difficult times at university or in their early careers — and not only lived to tell the tale, but bounced back stronger as a result.
Hosted and produced by Chris Stewart. Featuring: York graduates Sam Bourne and Natalie Greenwood, and Leeds graduate Jonathan Foster

      </description>
      <link>href="http://dev.wripa.ac.uk/potential"</link>
      <enclosure 
        length="24459417" 
        type="audio/mp3" 
        url="https://dev.wripa.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Potential_Advice_s1e5.mp3"
      />
      <guid>potpods1e4</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:24:56</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>

    <item>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:episode>3</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
      <title>Changing Direction</title>
      <description>
Sometimes in life you start down a road, only to find it's a dead-end. Or there's a detour you have to take. Or you break down and have to stop for a while. In this episode we talk to physics graduates about unexpected changes in their careers, from shifting jobs to completely rethinking your whole life plan.
Hosted and produced by Chris Stewart. Featuring: Leeds graduate Jonathan Foster, and York graduates Xanthe Edge, Natalie Greenwood and Harry Phillips
      </description>
      <link>href="http://dev.wripa.ac.uk/potential"</link>
      <enclosure 
        length="22553253" 
        type="audio/mp3" 
        url="https://dev.wripa.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Potential_Change_s1e3.mp3"
      />
      <guid>potpods1e3</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:23:59</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:episode>2</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
      <title>You're An Imposter</title>
      <description>
Whether it's lugging a backpack over a summer break, or packing your life into boxes and moving around the world for a new job, travel is transformative. We speak to three physics graduates about the highs and lows of exploring the globe— for work, sure, but also for the challenge, the growth and the joy of immersing yourself in another culture.
Hosted and produced by Chris Stewart. Featuring: York graduates Calum Lennox and Harry Phillips, and Leeds graduate Lottie Tant
      </description>
      <link>href="http://dev.wripa.ac.uk/potential"</link>
      <enclosure 
        length="29049556" 
        type="audio/mp3" 
        url="https://dev.wripa.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Potential_WITW_s1e2.mp3"
      />
      <guid>potpods1e2</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:29:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>
   
    <item>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:episode>1</itunes:episode>
      <itunes:season>1</itunes:season>
      <title>You're An Imposter</title>
      <description>
How on earth did I get into this degree? Why did anyone hire me for this job? I'm a total fraud — and one day they're going to realise, and throw me out. Sound familiar? You're not alone: pretty much everyone experiences Impostor Syndrome at some point. We've assembled a bunch of physics graduates who've been there, faced the self-doubt, and come through the other side. They're here to share their wisdom and tips for talking back to the voices of doubt. If they can do it, so can you. 
Hosted and produced by Chris Stewart. Featuring: York graduates Xanthe Edge, Natalie Greenwood and Calum Lennox, and Leeds graduates Nicola Brown, Jonathan Foster and Lottie Tant
      </description>
      <link>href="http://dev.wripa.ac.uk/potential"</link>
      <enclosure 
        length="22146265" 
        type="audio/mp3" 
        url="https://dev.wripa.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/Potential_Imposter_s1e1.mp3"
      />
      <guid>potpods1e1</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 13:00:00 EST</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:22:32</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>    

    <item>
      <itunes:episodeType>trailer</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:title>Potential Trailer</itunes:title>
      <description>
Potential is all about navigating your way from physics degree to new career — whatever that looks like for you! Featuring wise physics graduates from a network of UK universities. Hosted and produced by Chris Stewart, and brought to you by WRIPA, the White Rose Industrial Physics Academy.
      </description>
      <enclosure 
        length="22146265" 
        type="audio/mpeg" 
        url="https://dev.wripa.ac.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/Potential_Imposter_s1e1.mp3"
      />
      <guid>potpods1t</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <itunes:duration>00:22:32</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    </item>  


  </channel>
</rss>